EMERSON: It's life or death now, James.
不是无期就是死刑 詹姆斯
By that, I mean you're doing one or the other
要么死
up in Rockview.
要么在罗克维优监狱了此一生
This here is District Attorney Rodin.
这位是地方检查官 罗丁
Want to know what he's wondering?
知道她对你的看法吗
Whether you're gonna walk like a man or cry like a pussy
你或像男人那样走出去
on your way to the death house.
或像女人哭啼地走进死囚牢房
See, the D.A. likes the needle,
知道吗 检察官喜欢用针注射
whereas me,
然而我
I like to see a man like you live a long life
我很想让你长命百岁
with all your teeth knocked out.
直到你所有牙都被打掉
Passed around till a brother can't tell your fart from a yawn.
被众人多的狱友同志暴菊
Now, I don't know what kind of man you are,
放屁都不响
which of these two fates you prefer,
不知道你喜欢哪一种命运
but Rodin here is a generous fellow. He's willing to let you take your pick.
罗丁是个仁慈的人 他会让你自己选择
If you save us and this city a long and costly trial,
如果你不想耗时费力
waive your right to counsel and confess, right now.
那就放弃聘请律师 马上承认罪行 立刻
Sixteen hours.
16个小时了
Has to be some kind of record, Detective.
侦探 该有结果了
What the hell is this?
这是什么意思
Who the hell is Jack Reacher?
杰克-雷彻是什么人
Jack Reacher,
杰克-雷彻 乳名杰克
born Jack, not John, no middle name, is a ghost.
阿勒格尼县 地方检察官 没有中间名 像个幽灵
No credit cards, no credit history. No P.O. box, cell phone, e-mail.
没有信用卡和用卡记录 没有手机 电子邮箱 什么都没有
Nothing.
没有
Can you at least tell me who he is?
至少能告诉我他是谁吧
Well, I can tell you who he was. Blood military.
可以告诉你他以前是谁 他家几代都是军人
Born and raised on bases abroad.
在国外的军事基地出生长大
Mother was a French national, father in the Corps.
母亲是法国人 父亲在海军陆战队服役
His first trip to the United States was to attend West Point.
学校是是西点军校
Four years later, he ships out for good.
四年以后 到海外执行任务
Iraq. Afghanistan. The Balkans. You name it.
伊拉克 阿富汗 巴尔干半岛 都去过
Served with distinction.
出色地完成了各种任务
Silver Star, Bronze Star, Legion of Merit.
获得银星勋章 青铜星章 功勋勋章
Defence Superior Service Medal? Had to look that one up.
-国防部服役优秀勋章 -查查还有什么奖
And a Purple Heart. He spent the bulk of his service
还有紫心勋章 大部分服役时间都是在宪兵队度过的 据传他是个非常杰出的特工
Apparently, a troublemaker, too.
但显然也是个麻烦制造者
Demoted to Captain.
被降职为上尉
Worked his way back to Major.
后来又升到了上校
Then two years ago, he musters out.
两年前他申请退役
After a literal lifetime in the military, he just up and quits. And then,
在部队里度过了大部分时间
for only the second time in his life,
又突然退伍
he enters the United States and simply disappears.
然后第二次进入美国 之后就从人间蒸发了
RODIN: Dead, maybe?
死了？
EMERSON: Not according to Social Security
不
and a bank account in Virginia.
根据社保和弗吉尼亚银行帐户信息看
His pension is deposited monthly
他的退休金按月存入
and someone is making the occasional withdrawal. All wire transfers.
有人通过银行转帐把钱取走(西联银行)
I can't find out where without a federal warrant.
没有联邦搜查令 无法查出在哪取钱
RODIN: Well, he can't drive or fly.
他不开车 也不开飞机
At least not under his real name.
至少不是真名
- Any warrants? EMERSON: - Records clean.
有拘捕令吗 有没有犯罪记录
Oh, come on! A guy this hard to find? Gotta be wanted for something.
算了吧 这么难找的人 一定能找到理由通缉他
His record is clean.
他没有任何犯罪记录
So.
那么
How do we find this Reacher?
怎么才能找到这个雷彻
Obviously, you don't find this guy unless he wants to be found.
你无法找到 除非他想让你找到他
Excuse me, sir. There's a Jack Reacher here to see you.
打扫一下长官 有个叫杰克-雷彻的人想见你
Can I help you?
你有什么事吗
James Barr.
詹姆斯-巴尔
So, now you've seen him. How do you know him?
好了 你见过他了 你们怎么认识的
Why wasn't he in protective custody?
为什么不对他实行保护性监禁
That was an oversight.
是工作疏忽
More like some Corrections flunky threw him to the wolves.
是监狱里的势利小人把他扔进了狼窝
EMERSON: Just as likely.
好像是这样
But it's done and we can't undo it.
可是事到如今已经无法挽回
So what happens now?
现在怎么样了
Well, now he's in a coma.
好吧 现在他处在昏迷中
We'll try him when he wakes up. If he wakes up.
他昏迷不醒
Okay? Now it's your turn, Reacher.
如果他能醒过来 我们要审判他 好了该你谈谈了 雷彻
Why did he call you as a witness?
他为什么要你做证人
I don't believe he did.
我不相信他会这么做
Well, I believe he asked for you by name.
他指名道姓要你来
Any chance I could look at the evidence?
我能看一下证据吗
No way. Not till you answer some questions.
你回答完几个问题再说
Nice meeting you.
很高兴认识你
- Hey. Hey. Hey! - Mr Reacher.
嗨 嗨 嗨! 站住 雷彻先生
- Mr Reacher! - Hey, stop! Stop right there!
- 嘿 别动 - 嗨，站在原地别动
We had a deal.
我们有有言在先
I take you to Barr, you tell me what you know.
我带你去见巴尔 你告诉我你了解的情况
I know you say he shot five people, I know he's in a coma.
你说他射杀了五个人 可是他昏迷不醒
I know there's a bus station three miles away
有个公交车站
and I can walk there in 24 minutes.
我用24分钟走到那
So you're just going to walk out on your friend?
你要放弃你的朋友
- He's not my friend. - Why'd he ask for you, then?
- 他不是我的朋友 - 那他为什么会要求你来
Well, same reason he shot five people, he's crazy.
跟他杀死五个人是一个原因
Hey. Hold on.
他疯了 等一下
Don't do that.
别拦着我
HELEN: Well, this is a new low, even for both of you.
你们俩这么做卑鄙了
You do not talk to my client without me present.
没有我在场 你们不能和我的委托人谈话
You know that.
你知道
RODIN: We weren't talking to your client. He's in a coma, for Christ's sakes.
我们没有和他谈话 他处在昏迷之中
- You're Barr's attorney? - Helen Rodin, Jack Reacher.
- 你是巴尔的律师 - 海伦-罗丁 杰克-雷彻
- Jack Reacher? - Helen Rodin.
- 杰克-雷彻? - 海伦罗丁
Yeah, she's the District Attorney's daughter.
是的 她是地方检察官的女儿
It's a good story, actually.
这事儿说来话长
How'd you find him? How'd they find you?
你们是怎么找到他的
You can't be talking to this man. Two strikes in one day.
你不能和这个人谈话
- It's not what it looks like. - He came to us.
不是你想像的那样 是他找到的我们
- You went to the D.A.? - Is there a law against that?
- 你见了检察官 - 这样做违法吗
None you're currently breaking.
目前你还没有违法
Come on, before this gets awkward. Now, hey.
行啦 别把大家搞得下不来台
Say, "See you in court." For me.
快说 法庭上见
Good bye, Detective.
再见侦探
- Weird meeting you. - Likewise.
- 很高兴认识你 - 我也是
Let's go.
走吧
So, you're Jack Reacher.
你是杰克-雷彻 你是检察官的女儿
- So you're the D.A.'s daughter. - Oh, Jesus. Please.
走吧
- Is that even legal? - Fortunately.
－上帝 这种工作关系合法吗 －幸运的是合法
- How does that happen? - I'll tell you after deposition.
－怎么会有这种安排 －你宣誓作证之后再告诉你
You don't want to depose me.
别让我宣誓作证
Oh, well, you're my only defence witness.
你是被告证人
- I'm not a defence witness. - Your friend James thinks you are.
- 我不是 - 你的朋友詹姆斯认为你是
He's not my friend. Why does everyone assume that?
为什么所有人都认为他是我朋友
Well, why else would he ask for you
为什么所有人都认为他是我的朋友
and why would you come here to help him?
他要求见你 你来帮助他
I didn't come here to help him. I came here to bury him.
我不是来帮助他 是为了把他埋了
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(布鲁希尔建筑公司)
Linsky.
林斯基
Who the hell is Jack Reacher?
杰克-雷彻是什么人
HELEN: - So why are you so hard to find? - I'm impossible to find.
-你为什么这么难找 - 不可能找到我的
Why is that?
为什么找不到
Well, you could say it started out as an exercise and became an addiction.
这么说吧 这是我的职业习惯
Are you on the run?
你逃跑吗
My bus is leaving. You better hurry, counsellor.
我的车要开了 快点吧 律师
How do you know James Barr?
你是怎么认识巴尔的
- Why are you representing him? - I'm a lawyer.
-你为什么要替他辩护 -我是律师
So is a public defender, with just as much chance of clearing Barr.
公共辩护人也有机会证明他无罪
I'm not trying to clear him,
我并不是想证明他无罪
I am just trying to keep him off death row.
而是要他不被判死刑
- By proving he's insane? - Well, that's one option.
-你想证明他精神失常 -这也是一种选择
And sticking it to your father because...
跟你爸爸做对
No. Not my father. The Office of the District Attorney.
不是他 是地方检察官办公室
Because the Office of the District Attorney never bought you a pony.
因为地方检察官办公室从未承认你是淑女
D.A. Rodin's never lost a capital case. You know why?
罗丁检察官从未打输过死刑的案件 知道为什么吗
Impeccable tailoring.
政客都爱仗势欺人
- He never picks a fight he can't win. - Worked for the Red Baron.
-他从来都不接打不赢的案子 -知己知彼
Every murder suspect in this town is given a choice.
每个谋杀嫌疑犯都有两个选择
Confess or face death.
认罪或者面对死刑
Against a D.A. who never loses.
和从未输过的检察官打官司
My firm has reason to believe more than one innocent man
我的律师事务所相信无罪的人
has gone down without a fight.
但都会毫不抵抗就认罪伏法
Oh, I get it.
我明白了
You're an idealist.
你是个理想主义者
No. I'm a pacifist.
不 我是和平主义者
It's a noble crusade.
想废除死刑是高尚行为
But this is not the fight. Trust me. James Barr's guilty.
但这次你打不赢 相信我 詹姆斯-巴尔有罪
You haven't even seen the evidence.
你还没看证据呢
Is this a privileged conversation?
这是保密谈话吗
Of course, it's a client conference. Nothing you say here can be repeated.
对 是对诉讼委托人的谈话 你说的每一句话都不能转述
There are four types of people who join the military.
有四种人会参军
For some, it's a family trade.
有人是为了家族荣誉
Others are patriots, eager to serve.
有爱国者渴望为国效劳
Next, you have those who just need a job.
还有些为了工作
Then there's the kind who want a legal means of killing other people.
最后一类是想要一种合法的杀人方式
James Barr was one of those.
詹姆斯-巴尔就是这种人
He made sniper.
他当上了狙击手
Trained hard. Two thousand rounds a week.
刻苦训练 一周2000次
And with every shot, he's taught to visualise
每枪都要求射中脑门
the base of a man's skull through his reticle.
就是要一击致命
The sweet spot where the medulla meets the spine.
出血少 死的快
Finally, he's deployed to Iraq.
他终于被派往伊拉克
He's put on overwatch.
安排他去掩护射击组
All day long he stares through a scope at civilians.
日复一日 他通过瞄准镜盯着平民
Women.
女人
Children.
孩子
Day in, day out, for two long years
日复一日 漫长的2年
without ever once being cleared to fire a single shot.
没接到命令发过一枪
Then comes the drawdown.
后来开始撤军
For James Barr, the war's over.
对詹姆斯-巴尔来说 战争结束了
Two thousand rounds a week.
一周射击2000次
A quarter million rounds in his career, not one at a human target.
他职业生涯总共射击25万次 竟然没有一枪是真人做靶子
You've been hungry. You've been horny.
人处于饥饿之中 会饥不择食
You've had an itch you can't scratch.
身上痒痒又挠不着
Imagine that feeling. Days. Weeks. Years.
想像那种感觉
Imagine that feeling times 200,000, plus 50,000 more.
天天年年 这种难受要经历25万次
Imagine it's 130 degrees on the deck and tomorrow you're going home
设想一下 在54度的高温下站岗 明天就要回家了 知道吗
and you know if you don't scratch that itch now,
如果你现在不挠痒痒 就永远没机会了
you never will.
需要发泄一下
You need a release.
需要一个目标
You need a target.
需要找一个目标
And the who of it never once enters your mind.
而他的大脑从未有过明确目标
He covered his tracks well,
他隐蔽得非常好
just like sane people do.
跟神志清醒的人一样
He almost got away with it, too. But I caught him. And he confessed.
可是我抓到了他 事实面前他认了罪
So why didn't he go to prison?
那他为什么没进监狱
What Barr didn't know that day was the four civilian contractors he'd picked off
巴尔不知道他杀的安保人员
just spent the weekend at what they call a rape-rally.
是参加过集体强奸晚会的人
It was 28 women, ages 54 on down to 11.
28个女人 从11岁到54岁
Those were just the ones I could find before the case was shut down.
这些人是我在结案前找到的
See, the deeper I dug, the uglier it got.
挖得越深 越令人发指
And after seven long years of "Mission Accomplished,"
七年 伟大的任务之后
someone in the corporation just wanted the whole thing to end quietly.
安保公司的人想隐瞒真相
So they chalked it up to the fog of war, made the murders go away.
把此案归结为战争导致的人精神失常 让杀人犯一走了之
This is classified information.
这是绝密信息
And that's why the privilege.
所以是保密谈话
But you were ready to tell this to the D.A.
但你可以把这些告诉检察官
The last time I saw Barr, I made him a promise.
我上次见到巴尔时 向他做过承诺
And when I saw his name on the news, I came here to keep it.
当我看到这个消息 就过来兑现承诺
- But now I know I don't have to. - How can you be sure?
-现在知道不用这么做了 -你怎么会这么肯定
You still haven't seen the evidence.
你还没有看过证据
Your father has. And he doesn't pick a fight he can't win.
你父亲看过了 他不会接打不赢的官司
Barr's not getting away with murder again.
巴尔不会再逃脱杀人罪名
He might.
有可能
He suffered a severe brain injury in state custody.
在监狱里 他大脑受到严重损伤
When he wakes up, if he wakes up,
如果他能醒来
he may not remember the event, he may not remember anything at all.
可能会不记得这件事 或者什么都不记得
And this case won't be about James Barr's guilt or innocence.
这个案子不是巴尔有罪或无罪
It'll be about his ability to stand trial.
而是他能否接受审判
After everything I just told you, you still want to defend him?
我把一切都告诉了你 你还想为他辩护吗
I want to see he gets a fair trial.
我想看到他受到公正的审判
You said he confessed in Baghdad.
你说过他在巴格达已经认罪了
He didn't confess this time.
他这次没有承认
- This time he knows better. - This time he asked for you.
这次他做的孽更多 他要求见你
I want to know why.
我想要知道为什么
You want to know why. I can see it's eating you.
你想要知道为什么 这次他做的孽更多 他要求见你
And you can't ask Barr,
你无法问巴尔
and the D.A. won't let you see the evidence.
检察官又不让你看证据
My lead investigator has complete access to the evidence. All of it.
我的首席调查员可以看出那些证据
- So where's your lead investigator? - About to catch a bus out of town.
你的首席调查员在哪儿   他要出城了
Thanks for the coffee, counsellor.
谢谢你的咖啡 律师
You understand you're not just asking me to look at the evidence.
你要明白 你不仅让我看证据
You're asking me to look at a cold-blooded killer.
还要让我看那个准备杀手
A man I know to be guilty. A man you want to keep off death row.
我知道她是个有罪的人
And you're asking me to look at him objectively.
即使你不想看到他被判死刑
Yes, that is what I'm asking.
你要求我客观地看待他
I'll do it. On one condition.
是的 这就是我的要求
Name it.
我接了 但有一个条件 说吧
You have to look at the victims objectively.
你必须客观地看待受害者
How do you suggest I do that?
你建议我怎么做
- Yes? - Mr Farrior?
谁 法里奥尔先生吗
I'm Helen Rodin. We spoke on the phone.
我是海伦-罗丁 我们通过电话
Of course.
当然
You said you're defending the man that ki...
你要为那人辩护
HELEN: I represent James Barr, yes.
我要做詹姆斯-巴尔的辩护律师
FARRIOR: And you have questions about my daughter?
你要问关于我女儿的问题吗
HELEN: I do.
是的
FARRIOR: What for?
为什么
I was hoping to get a better sense of who the victims were as...
我希望了解受害者是什么人
That is to say, who they were as people.
就是说 他们是什么样人
That's a bit unusual, considering your position, isn't it?
考虑到你的地位 这不正常 是不是
That is true.
说得对
Normally someone in my position would want the jury
通常情况下 处在我这个地位的人
to know as little as possible about the...
应该让陪审团知道得越少越好
FARRIOR: The people that your client killed.
你的当事人杀了那么多人
In cold blood.
冷酷无情
Have you spoken with the other families?
你和其它家庭的人谈过了吗
Yeah, some. The ones who would speak with me.
是的, 有几个人愿意和我谈
Come in.
进来
Thank you.
谢谢
She had a little girl with her that day.
克里希姆是个保姆 那天她领着个小孩
Yes, I know.
是的 我知道
Are you gonna go talk with that child?
你要和那个孩子谈话吗
No, of course not. I...
不 当然不
Why not?
为什么不
- Well, I think it would be... - Insensitive?
我觉得有点太残酷
Inappropriate?
不合适
Everything that you want to know about my daughter
你想要知道关于我女儿的材料
is right here.
都在这
The Gazette did a nice piece on her.
报上对她作了全面的报道
Her obituary does the rest.
她的讣告上做了其它说明
Thank you. I'll definitely have a look.
谢谢 我一定好好看看
You a good attorney, Miss Rodin?
你是个好律师 罗丁小姐
- That's not really for me to... - Just
我真的不应该
answer the question.
别打岔
Yes, I suppose I am pretty good.
直接回答问题
Good enough to keep that man off death row?
是的 我认为自己是个优秀律师
You know,
你知道
I think maybe I should go.
优秀的足以能让巴尔免除死刑
You stay where you are.
也许我该走了    请等下
That man deserves to die, Miss Rodin.
那个人死有余辜
Why would you defend him?
你为什么要为他辩护
I can see that I have made a terrible mistake.
我犯了严重的错误
And I'm very, very sorry and I promise I won't bother you again.
非常抱歉 我保证再也不来打扰您
Hello, Dad.
哈罗,爸爸
What the hell are you doing?
你在干什么
What am I... What?
我在干什么 怎么了
Is it true?
是真的吗
You're talking to the victims' families? You? Alone?
你在和受害者的家人谈话 你一个人
How do you know that? How did you find me here?
你怎么知道的
I'm the District Attorney. It's my business to know.
我是地方检察官居 了解情况是我的工作
That's not an answer.
这不是回答问题
Oh. Well, you're not the only one with crack investigators, Helen.
好了 你不是能力超强的调查员
That's right. I know about Reacher.
对了 我知道雷彻的情况
Your lead investigator is a war veteran
你的首席调查员
who's been missing for the last two years.
是失踪两年的老兵
How can you vouch for his state of mind?
你如何能担保他情绪稳定
How can you trust anything he tells you?
并相信他 告诉你的一切
You don't know the man.
你根本不了解他
Tell me this, does he know you can't pay him?
告诉我
That your own firm didn't want this case?
他知道你不能付他报酬吗
That nobody wants this case?
你的律师不想接这个案子吗
You never even spoke to your client before he wound up in a coma.
没人愿意接这个案子 在你的委托人醒来之前
Oh, now listen to me! Listen. Listen, I'm speaking as your father.
你从未和他谈过话 听我说 听着 我是作为你的父亲和你说话
Whatever our differences have been in the past,
无论我们之间有何分岐
you gotta listen to me now.
你都应该听我的
You're making a terrible mistake.
你正在犯一个可怕的错误
You cannot win this case.
你不能够赢得这场官司
You're going to ruin your career. Why? For what?
会毁了你的事业 为了什么 为了什么
To hurt me? To change me?
为了伤害我吗
- Helen... - Don't touch me!
- 海伦 - 别碰我
REACHER: Thanks for letting me take a look.
谢谢让我参观
Hey. We love it when friends of the accused
我们喜欢被告的朋友
try to tear our work to shreds.
把我们的工作贬得一无是处
He's not my friend.
他不是我的朋友
So you keep saying. Find any holes?
你接着说 发现什么漏洞了吗
Well, you didn't have to put him in the hospital.
你们没必要让他住进医院
Other than that, damn fine police work. It's open and shut.
除此之外 警察的工作也干得很漂亮
What can I say? The scene was a gold mine.
结案并不难 我能说什么呢 犯罪现场是座金矿
Come on. Now we both know gold's only as good as the man digging.
我们都知道只有高手才能挖到金子
Yeah, well, anytime you want to come back, take a look at this stuff...
你想来随时都可以
No, thanks. Don't need to.
不 谢谢 没这个必要
You never took any notes.
你从来不记笔记
Oh, I don't need to.
没必要
So you were some real hot shit in the Army, huh?
你可真是军队里的大能人
I did all right.
我干得还行吧
So what does an Army cop do mostly? Break up bar fights?
军队里都干些什么
I did what you do pretty much, with one minor difference.
给酒吧斗殴的人拉架 不 我和你不一样
What's that?
只有一点区别 什么区别
Every suspect was a trained killer.
每个嫌疑犯都是训练有素的杀手
Thanks again.
再次谢谢
Why do you think he paid for parking?
你认为他为什么要付费停车
He's about to fire six shots into a crowd of strangers.
他向陌生的人发射6颗子弹
And he's worried about the meter maid?
会担心女抄表员给他罚单
"Simple loony" won't do it for you?
精神病 解释不通吗
I like to have at least one alternate theory.
我喜欢有另外一个推理
Habit.
习惯
Muscle memory.
肌肉记忆
I don't think he knew he was doing it.
他不知道自己在做这种事
Like I said, it's damn fine work.
我说过了 干得真漂亮
Hey, Army.
大兵
What's the serial number on the rifle?
步枪上面的序列号是多少
What's the date on the quarter?
硬币上面的年份是哪一年
Forest for the trees, Detective.
只见树木
Forest for the trees.
不见森林 侦探
Mind if I share your table?
不介意一起坐吧
I'm Sandy.
我是桑迪
So was I. Last week.
沙地 我上周去过沙地
On a beach, in Florida.
在海滩上 佛罗里达
What's your name?
你的名字
Jimmie Reese.
吉米瑞斯
You don't look like a Jimmie.
你看上去不像是吉米
What do I look like?
那像谁
I don't know. But not a Jimmie.
我不知道 但不像吉米
So you're new in town?
你是新来的吧
Usually.
算是吧
It's kind of loud in here.
这里太吵了
Do you want to maybe go someplace quieter? I have a car.
你也许想去静一点的地方 我有车
You're old enough to drive?
你够开车的年龄吗
I'm old enough to do a lot of things.
我到了能做很多事情的年龄
I'm on a budget, Sandy.
我在节省开始 桑迪
What?
什么
I can't afford you.
我买不起你
I'm not a hooker.
我不是妓女
Oh, then I really can't afford you.
我真的没钱和你处朋友
Seriously, I work at the auto parts store.
认真点 我在汽车零件商店工作
What I mean is, the cheapest woman tends to be the one you pay for.
我是说 人们都愿意花最少钱玩儿女人
I am not a hooker!
我不是妓女
No. A hooker would get the joke.
我不过开个玩笑
MAN: - What's this? - He called me a whore.
-这是在干什么 -他说我是妓女
Is that true?
那是真的吗
Well, nobody said whore. She inferred hooker, but I meant slut.
好吧 没人说她是妓女 而我说她是荡妇
Hey. That's our sister.
她是我们的妹妹
Is she a good kisser?
她是接吻高手吗
Hey. Outside.
出去
Pay your cheque first.
先把帐结了
I'll pay later.
我一会儿再付
You won't be able to.
一会儿就付不了了
You think?
你认为会是这样吗
All the time. You should try it.
一直是 你试试看
It's a great joke, but I'm going to beat your ass.
我要狠揍你一顿
Do you want to do that here or outside?
你想在这里打还是外面
Outside.
外面
Stay here, Sandy.
呆在这里 桑迪
I don't mind the sight of blood.
我不介意看见血
When it means you're not pregnant, anyway.
看见出血 你才像个姑娘
You still think you're funny now, creep?
你还以为你是个牛仔 傻瓜
Shut your mouth, Sandy! No one is talking to you.
闭嘴 桑迪 没人跟你说话
It's your last chance to walk away.
你现在走还来得及
Are you kidding? It's five against one.
你在开玩笑吗 五对一
It's three against one.
三对一 你不识数吗
How do you figure?
我只要先打倒你
Well, once I take out the leader, which is you,
就能轻易解决那两个跟屁虫
I'll have to contend with one or two enthusiastic wingmen.
最后两个人
The last two guys, they always run.
就会逃之夭夭
Oh, you've done this before?
你以前干过这种事
Yeah.
是的
It's getting late.
天不早了
Remember,
记住
you wanted this.
这是你自找的
It's okay. You're okay.
好了 你完蛋了
- Get up. (GROANS LOUDLY)
起来
Okay.
好
Now we know who's who.
现在知道谁是跟屁虫了
Let's get this done.
我们把架打完吧
Really?
还想打吗
Shit!
该死
On the ground!
趴在地上
That's a pretty impressive response time, fellas.
伙计们反应也太神速了
COP 1: Do it!
趴下
COP 2: Hands behind your back.
手放在背后
Who hired you?
谁雇的你
COP 2: Let's go.
走
Hey, Helen.
嗨 海伦
HELEN: Am I wearing too much perfume?
我是不是喷了太多的香水
Breathing too sternly. Detective Emerson.
我有鼻炎 爱默生侦探
- Somebody dead? - And if someone is?
- 有人死了吗? - 如果死了呢
Then they died of shame. 'Cause I was being gentle.
那他们也是羞辱死的 我下手很轻
I'm starting to understand why you move around a lot, Reacher.
我现在明白你为什么到处走 雷彻
REACHER: So no one's dead.
有人死了么
One guy likely won't ever walk right again.
有个小子可能再也走不了路了
REACHER: You want to charge me. EMERSON: Very much.
-你想起诉我吗 -很想
But no one's pressing.
可是没有人要告我
Sadly, no.
很遗憾 没有
Am I free to go?
我可以自由了吗
Hey, Emerson.
爱默生
4862681.
4862681.
What's that?
那是什么
It's the serial number on Barr's rifle.
巴尔步枪上面的序列号
You're working for me, do you understand that?
你在为我工作 知道吗
So everything you do is a reflection on my firm. On me.
你做的每件事都给我的律师所
I was set up.
造成恶劣的影响
You're talking to a lawyer.
-我被人陷害了 -你在和律师说话
There was this girl. She came onto me. Picked a fight.
有个女孩 她主动找我 故意找茬
Which never happens in a bar.
这事总在酒吧发生
She was thrown when I told her my name.
当我告诉她我叫什么名字时
She was expecting Mike Tyson?
她很吃惊 她遇到了拳王泰森
She wasn't expecting Jimmie Reese.
她不相信我是吉米瑞斯
Yankees second baseman.
扬基队的二垒手
Why did you say you were a Yankees second baseman?
为什么你要说是二垒手
I always use Yankees second basemen.
我一直使用扬基队二垒手的名字
I didn't say I was a Yankees second baseman, I just said...
又没说我就是扬基队的二垒手
Look, the point is,
现在重点是
she was expecting to hear "Jack Reacher."
是她想听到杰克-雷彻这个名字
She knew who I was.
她知道我是谁
And the cops were rolling before the fight even started.
还没打 警察就来了
And those five guys are her brothers? Come on.
这五个小子是她的哥哥 算了吧
Someone sent those boys to put me down.
有人派这几个小子来干掉我
Who?
谁
HELEN: If someone followed you at the river today,
如果今天有人跟踪你
it was probably a cop. And I highly doubt...
可能是警察
There are three things cops never do.
有三件事警察从来不做
They don't vote Democrat, they don't drive Cadillacs,
投民主党的票 开凯迪拉克
and they never use personal vehicles.
或者用私人汽车办案
It's not a cop.
不是警察
A P.I., then, or the D.A.'s office.
私人侦探或检察官办公室的人
You think your father's office would set me up?
你认为你父亲会陷害我
Why would anyone set you up?
为什么有人要害你
How was your day?
你有新线索
It went exactly the way I think
雷彻
you hoped it would.
你预计的事发生了
You Okay?
是吗
Mmm-hmm.
嗯
What'd you learn?
你有证据吗
HELEN: Chrissie Farrior was 22.
克里希-法里奥尔 22岁
A nanny caring for the six-year-old daughter of family friends.
是保姆 照顾家人和朋友6岁的女儿
She'd finally saved enough money for a trip to China,
她攒够了钱 要去中国旅游
in fact, she should have left the week before.
应该一周前启程
But the girl she cared for wanted Chrissie to stay for her 7th birthday.
可是她看的小女孩要留下来和她过七岁生日
They'd gone downtown that day to shop for a party dress.
她们去城里买生日晚会穿的衣服
Rita Coronado worked as a cleaning lady at the River Cross Plaza.
瑞塔-科罗娜多
She was usually late for work, but she had a good reason.
是十字河购物中心的清洁工人 她上班经常迟到
Since her son Marco was nine years old
因为她儿子马可9岁
she had to personally drop him at school to make sure he actually went.
她每天送儿子去学校
But her dedication had paid off.
她的付出得到了回报
Marco was now an honour student.
马可现在是名优秀学生
As a reward for all his hard work,
为了奖励儿子刻苦学习
Rita was taking him to his first baseball game.
瑞塔第一次带他去看棒球比赛
And she was on her way to pick up the tickets that very afternoon.
事发当天下午 她在买票的路上
Nancy Holt's last words to her husband were a lie.
南希霍尔特对她丈夫说的话是谎话
- I love you, babe. See you! - Bye.
- 我爱你孩子 再见 - 再见
She told him she was taking her car to be serviced,
她说要去保养汽车
but in fact, she was headed downtown.
却开去了市中心
It's perfect.
完美
She told the clerk she didn't want the purchase showing up on her credit card.
她告诉服务员 不想在信用卡上 留下买过东西的记录
She wanted to surprise her husband for their 10th anniversary
她想在结婚十周年纪念日 送给丈夫一个惊喜
Oline Archer never liked her husband's construction business,
奥赖恩-阿彻一直都不喜欢
even after helping him become one of the largest contractors in the county.
她丈夫的建筑生意
So it came as a relief when his failing health and a costly lawsuit
由于疾病缠身 加上昂贵的诉讼费用
were forcing them to sell to the competition.
他们被迫把公司卖给了竞争对手
Rob?
救命
Help! Help!
救命 救命
Her husband had given his life for the company.
她丈夫把一生都献给了公司
But now that it was hers,
现在公司属于她了
she couldn't bring herself to let it go.
她却不愿卖掉
She was on her way to secure a loan that day
那天 她为了保住她的生意
so she could keep the business she'd always hated.
去办理了抵押贷款
Darren Sawyer was an investment broker
达伦-索耶和瑞塔在同一楼里上班
in the same building where Rita worked.
是名投资经纪人
His wife said he'd grown increasingly distant of late.
她妻子说他回家越来越晚
She can't remember their last words to one another, but they weren't kind.
她不记得和丈夫上一次说话是什么时候 但说的话都很难听
Darren's body was found beside a fresh bouquet of roses
达伦的尸体旁有束玫瑰花
he'd bought that morning
是他那天早晨买的
and his wife takes comfort in the fact that, in his last moments,
让他妻子感到欣慰的是
he was most likely thinking of her.
丈夫在弥留之际还在思念她
We're gonna be okay.
我们会没事
REACHER: So what'd you learn?
你搜集到了什么证据
You want me to say you were right.
你是对的
You want me to say that this isn't the fight.
不应该打这个官司
James Barr should die.
詹姆斯-巴尔该死
Maybe he should.
他死有余辜
I meant, what did you learn about the victims.
我是说 有关遇害者的消息
What more do you want?
你想听什么
They were five innocent people senselessly murdered.
他们五个是无辜的
I'm sorry. Could you please put a shirt on?
莫名其妙地就被杀了 对不起 你穿上衬衫好吗
This is my shirt.
这就我的衬衫
You lose your luggage?
你失行李箱丢失了
I don't have any luggage.
我没行李
Uh, what was I saying?
我刚才说了什么
- Five innocent people. - Murdered at random, yes.
- 五个无辜的人 - 随意地被谋杀了 是的
You know how many people die in this country every year?
你知道在美国 每年有多少人死亡吗
Two and a half million.
250万人
That means every day,
每天
roughly 7,000 average Americans wake up for the last time.
约有七千美国人闭上眼睛
Last Friday, five of them converged on a single spot and died together.
上星期五 他们中的五个死在一起了
Is that random?
这是巧合吗
What else would you call it?
那你说是什么
Well, take Darren and Nancy. Odds are they were having an affair.
可能达伦和南希之间有婚外情
Excuse me?
你说什么
You don't buy roses for your wife on the way to work.
人们不会在上班路上给妻子买花
You buy them on the way home.
而是在回家的路上买
And you don't worry about a charge showing up on your credit card
正常人不会担心信用卡上的付款记录
when your anniversary is that weekend.
结婚纪念日在周末
Unless it's the gift you're hiding.
除非是想隐藏这个礼物
And that's why she kept walking
她一直向前走
while everyone else ran.
而其他人都在逃跑
You can't prove that.
你无法证明你的推论
How hard would it be? Cell phones, e-mails.
这很难吗 手机 电子邮件
All it takes is someone willing to dig.
只要有人愿意调查就行
What's your point exactly?
你想说什么
My point is that two of the victims weren't there strictly by chance.
那两个遇害人不是偶然相遇
I need a list of Barr's known associates.
我需要一份巴尔合伙人的名单
There isn't one. He didn't have any.
他没有合伙人 很孤僻
He's a classic loner. He didn't even talk to his neighbours.
他甚至都不和邻居说话
He was a quiet man. Never bothered anyone.
他是一个安静的人 从来不打扰别人
Yeah, exactly.
是的
- You have his credit card statement? - I can get it. Why?
- 你有他的信用卡记录吗 - 我能拿到 要它做什么
I need the list of all the places he hung out.
我需要他曾去过地方的清单 所有的地方
Bars, bowling alleys, strip clubs,
酒吧 球场 俱乐部
gun ranges.
射击场
Anywhere someone would remember him.
能记录到他去过的地方
What do we hope to find?
你希望找到什么
I need some sleep.
我需要睡一会儿
You, too.
你也是
You don't really think I'm gonna...
你不是想要
Be back to pick me up at 7:00.
七点钟回来接我
Yep. Absolutely.
好的
Who's with you?
你和谁在一起
What happened?
发生什么事了
Oh, that's him, isn't it?
哦是他 对不对
I ain't seeing you, man!
我看不见你
Relax. What happened?
放松 发生什么事
Barr's attorney hired an investigator.
巴尔的律师雇了一名调查员
Name of Reacher. Some sort of top-shelf Army cop.
叫雷彻  军队里的顶级高手
He was in Baghdad the same time as Barr.
他和巴尔同时在巴格达服役
So?
怎么了
So Barr asked for this soldier by name.
巴尔点名要这个大兵
Then he shows up at the river today. Then up on the highway.
他今天出现在高速公路桥
Almost like he knew something.
他好像知道我们的事
And you said we don't like people asking questions.
你说过不喜欢别人向我们提问题
No, we sure don't.
对不喜欢
So I took steps.
所以我采取了措施
You took steps.
你采取了措施
Local people. My guys.
当地人 我哥们
And it blew back on you.
你要遭报应了
I figured five guys would do it.
我以为他们五个人能解决问题
Mmm. This franchise was yours to manage.
你已经超越了你的权限 到此为止
That's all. Maintenance is our thing, you understand?
下一步是我们的事 明白吗
Yeah, I understand. I couldn't reach you!
我知道 我无法联系你
Well, that's how this works.
这是我们的工作方式
Well, I had to make a decision!
好吧 我必须作决定
- These locals, I want their names. - It's in the file.
- 这些本地人  我需要他们的名字 - 在文件中
Any of them know who you are?
他们中有人认识你吗
Just one, but I took care of it.
有一个 但我已经解决了
You...
你
(SIGHS) - Where's the body? - It's distributed.
-尸体在哪 -已经分尸了
Relax! No one's gonna find it.
放松 没有人去找它
- Suppose we want it found, yeah? - Why the hell would you want it found?
- 假如我们要找呢 - 为什么
'Cause we got a way of doing things so they stay done.
我们有自己的方式
Clean!
干净利落
A missing person isn't clean.
丢了一个人就干净了
Christ's sakes, man. You only had to kill one goddamn person.
你本想杀一人却殃及了五个人
You tapped five! You call that clean?
这就是你说的干净 我说的是不露马脚
I call it done. They're looking at the shooter, not the target.
他们找的是射手 不是靶子
Jesus.
上帝
We make it messy now so it won't get messy later.
现在事情一团糟 以后不能再乱了
And we don't leave questions unanswered ever.
我们不能留下任何问题
Okay, all right. Okay. I can fix this.
永久不留 好吧 我搞定
MAN: - Open your eyes. - No, I ain't seeing you!
-睁开你的眼睛 - 不 我没看你
MAN: It makes no difference now.
现在无所谓了
I made a mistake.
我犯错了
I mean, you can still use me, just tell me how to fix...
我还有用 告诉我怎么做
To survive. Don't say "fix it," because you can't.
要活命就别说搞不定 因为你搞不定
We covered up the one mess. You made another.
我们刚清理完一个乱摊子 你又弄出来一个
All right. You're right.
好 你说得对
You're right. You're absolutely right. I'm sorry.
真的没错 对不起
Just tell me what I have to do.
告诉我怎么做
I was in prison in Siberia.
我在西伯利亚的监狱中呆过
I spent my first winter wearing a dead man's coat.
我穿着死人的衣服 度过了严冬
A hole in one pocket.
口袋破了
I chewed these fingers off
为了不让冻伤变成坏疽
before the frostbite could turn to gangrene.
我就吃掉了这几个指头
These I gave up to avoid working in the sulphur mine.
这几个是为了逃避到硫矿劳动吃掉的
That is how I survived when so many others did not.
就这样 我活了下来 而许多人死了
A man this rare can always be of use.
像我这样的人 总会有用武之地
So show me. Show me you are rare.
做给我看 让我看看你有多坚强
Show me you'll do anything to survive.
让我看看为了生存 你会做任何事
I don't understand.
我不明白
The fingers from your left hand.
吃掉你左手的手指
Have you... Have you got a knife?
你有刀吗
Did I have a knife in Siberia?
我在西伯利亚里没有刀
No... Come on, you've got to be kidding.
算了吧 你在和我开玩笑
You can do it.
你办得到
Show me.
做给我看
Christ!
天呐
Can't! I can't.
不能 我不能
Always the bullet.
我真不明白
- I can't! - I don't understand.
还得用子弹
What do we do about the soldier?
我们怎么处理那个大兵
What we always do.
老办法
Barr's credit card statement. Eyewitness testimonies.
巴尔的信用卡对帐单 目击证人证词 咖啡
Coffee. You take it black, right?
没加牛奶吧
Yeah. What can I say? I take my work home.
我能说什么 我在家里工作
Afraid Barr's credit card statement's a dead end.
巴尔的信用卡对帐单是个死胡同
No bars, no strip joints, nothing. Pretty much just gas and groceries.
没有酒吧, 没有脱衣舞俱乐部 只有汽油和杂货店的帐单
I need you to look for gun ranges between 100 and 150 miles from here.
从这开始找  50到100英里内的射击场
Limit your search to ranges longer than 300 yards.
只找300码以上射击距离的射击场
Sure, if you tell me why.
可以 你能告诉我为什么
Barr consistently filled his tank on Saturday,
巴尔一直都在星期六给汽车加满油
and again on Sunday.
星期天再加满一次
He took a long drive almost every weekend.
说明周末是长途旅行
- He could be going anywhere. - Yes.
- 他可能去任何地方 - 是的
And if it's bars, bowling alleys or strip clubs, we'll never find it.
而且如果是酒吧 球场或脱衣舞俱乐部俱乐部 我们永远不会找它
But a Match-level gun range? There might be two.
比赛用的射击场呢
And he made his own bullets. That means he shot a lot.
原因有两个 他自己做子弹 或者练习射击
I'm guessing every Saturday.
我猜测每个星期六都要来
Maybe with a friend.
也许和一位朋友来
Why is it so important you talk to his friends?
为什么和他的朋友谈话那么重要
Assuming he had any.
如果他有朋友
Drop me at the auto parts store.
在汽车配件商店停一下
I... Wait. Which one?
等等 哪家
I don't know. She just said "the auto parts store."
她说的那家汽车配件商店
She? Who?
她 谁
Reacher, can you be a little more specific?
你能说具体点吗
I didn't say "an auto parts store."
我没说任何汽车配件商店
Which one stands out in your mind as the auto parts store?
你记忆中哪家配件商店最有名
HELEN: You want me to wait?
需要我等你吗
- No, I'll meet you back at the office later. HELEN: - How will you get there?
不用 我一会去办公室找你 你怎么去
I'll hitch a ride.
我搭车去
Can I help you?
你要买什么
Sandy work here?
桑迪在这里上班吗
What's this about?
你有什么事
So she does, thanks. I need to speak with her.
我有话和她说 是私事
It's a personal matter.
她在工作
- She's on the clock. - Legal personal matter.
合法工作
What are you, a cop?
长官 你要干什么
Call her out, Gary.
叫她出来
- I'm gonna need to see some I.D. - Go get Sandy.
加里 有证件吗 叫桑迪
Well, I need to see something.
好吧 我要看你的证件
How about the inside of an ambulance?
你想躺救护车里吗
Okay, I'm calling the police.
好 我报警
I don't think Sandy wants the police involved...
我想桑迪不想让警察参与此事
Hey! You...
嗨  你
Hello? I need some help. Hello? Hey! You!
哈罗  我需要一些帮忙
No. You are not allowed back in here, man!
你 后面不允许去
Shit.
该死
You know this guy?
你认识这个人吗
Tell him.
告诉他
Give us a few, Gary.
你先出去 加里
Listen, I wasn't... I didn't know.
听着 我不是  我不知道
I didn't know that was going to happen!
我不知道会发生那样的事
It was Jeb.
都怪杰布
The big guy.
那个大个子
Jeb Oliver.
杰布-奥利沃
He told me you were a predator. You were supposed to star groping me.
他告诉我你是个猛男 我以为你能上勾
Just don't hurt me.
别伤害我
Sandy, sit down.
桑迪 坐下
Where can I find Jeb?
我到哪能找到杰布
I don't know. He didn't come to work today.
我不知道 他今天没来上班
So he works here.
他在这儿上班
Yeah.
是的
It's bullshit, though. He cooks crystal.
他贩卖冰毒 是个疯子
His address, write it down.
把他地址写下来
I'm really sorry, mister.
真的很抱歉 先生
You were supposed to be a pervert.
你是个坐怀不乱的人
And it was an easy 100 bucks.
我差点赚到100元
That's all?
就那么点儿吗
When Jeb asks, you do what he says.
杰布让我做 我就得按他说的做
Am I in trouble?
我有麻烦吗
Not if you lend me your car.
把你的车借给我就没麻烦
- I don't have a car. - Well, sure you do. It's outside.
- 我没有车 - 你当然有 就在外面
I'm guessing you're the Camaro.
我猜那辆卡玛洛是你的
That whimsy little pickup has Gary written all over it. Keys?
把那辆小皮卡借给我
I can't. It's Jeb's car!
我不能 那是杰布的车
Well, won't he be surprised when I drive it home for him.
我把车开到他家去 他是不会感到惊讶的
Who are you, mister?
你是什么人 先生
Really?
真的吗
I'm just a guy who wants to be left alone.
我只是一个不愿意被打扰的人
I get off work at six!
我六点下班
Maybe we could...
也许我们可以
Sandy, listen.
桑迪 听着
Now, you seem like a sweet girl.
你是个可爱女孩
You're pretty.
你很漂亮
You're obviously sharp,
聪明
doing Gary's books for him.
给加里管帐
You don't have to let these guys use you.
你不能让这些家伙利用你
It's just what girls like me do.
我这样的女孩只能干这个
You got money?
你有钱吗
A little.
有一点
Get out of town for a couple of days.
你要出城几天
Why?
为什么
Get out of town, Sandy.
去外地 桑迪
Is Jeb home?
杰布在家吗
I have a warrant to search the premises.
我有房屋搜查令
I see.
知道了
Well, if you don't mind...
好吧 如果你不介意
I got this!
我有这个
Okay, okay.
好吧
All right.
好
Don't move.
不许动
I'll tell you what.
我告诉你
When I move, you pull the trigger.
我要是动 你就开枪
- Where's Jeb? - He's not here.
- 杰布在哪 - 他不在这里
Where can I find him?
我在哪能找到他
Jesus! My hand!
我的手
Well, you shouldn't play with guns. Where can I find him?
你不该玩枪 我在哪能找到他
You're the one driving his car. You tell... (CRIES OUT)
你开他的车 应该你告诉我才对
The last I saw him, we was all leaving jail.
我上次见到他 是出狱那天
He said he had to see a guy.
他说他必须见一个人
- What guy? Who? - I don't know.
- 什么人 谁 - 我不知道
I don't know, I swear.
我不知道 我发誓
Next I know, his mom woke up from a bender
他妈妈吸多了
and his shit's all gone.
他醒来后所有的东西就都丢了
Is he the sort to light out like that?
他是那种不辞而别的人吗
No, no, man. He'd never leave his moms alone.
不是 他从来不丢下他妈妈不管
Shit ain't right.
这事有点不对劲
- Got a car? - It's outside.
- 你有车吗 - 在外面
Keys.
钥匙
My hand, man. They're in my pock... Aah!
我的手 在我口袋里
Okay, okay.
好 好
Now look at your friends.
看看你的朋友
Now look at my face.
现在看我的脸
Do you ever want to see me again?
还想见我吗
No way.
决不
Am I stealing your car?
我在偷你的汽车吗
Use it as long as you like.
你想用多久都行
You're very kind.
你真讲究
Ah!
啊
REACHER: I think Jeb Oliver's dead.
我认为杰布已经死了
- Who's Jeb Oliver? - He was the guy from the bar.
- 谁是杰布 - 酒吧里那家伙
Jesus, how hard did you hit him?
天啊 你把他打成什么样了
What? No, not me.
不是我
No, he was murdered.
是他杀
And someone tried to make it look like he left town.
凶手想造成他离开城里的假象
Well, maybe he just left town.
也许他真是走了
You pack your shower curtain when you travel?
旅行还把浴帘装到行李中吗
Is this what you base your conclusions on?
这是你的结论吗
What is that on your head?
你头怎么了
You don't want to know.
你不会想知道的
You said on the phone you wanted to submit your findings.
你想提交你的调查结果
James Barr was a sniper. Not the best, not the worst.
詹姆斯-巴尔 是个狙击手 不是最好, 也不是最差的
But he trained non-stop for two years.
但是受过两年训练
What does training like that do?
这种训练能起什么作用
What does any training do?
任何训练都有作用
Skills become reflex. Muscle memory. You do without thinking.
技术变成反射 肌肉记忆 你不用思考
It also makes people who aren't necessarily smart seem smart
把战术灌给他们
by beating some tactical awareness into them.
使不聪明的人看上去很聪明
Now, 99% of the evidence your father has against Barr
99%的证据指控巴尔
didn't exist in Baghdad,
在巴格达都没有发现
not because Barr was smart, but because he was trained.
不是因为巴尔聪明 而是因为他受过训练
See, from that garage, the shooter had the sun in his eyes.
在那个停车场开枪 射手的眼睛会受到阳光照射
Targets were moving left and right. It's difficult conditions for any sniper.
目标左右移动 对任何射手来说 都很难击中
But Baghdad, you said Barr was in a parking garage then.
但是在巴格达 巴尔在停车场里
Because in Baghdad, the sun's behind him.
因为在巴格达 太阳照在他背后
Targets coming straight ahead, single file.
目标是从正前方过来 列成一队
Ideal conditions for even an average shooter
对普通射手来说 这是最理想的条件
and the exact same conditions
同样的条件
he would've had up on that highway bridge.
他在高速公路桥上也能找到
Up there, he would never even have to get out of the van.
在桥上 他甚至都不用下车
No parking meter.
没有停车计时器
No camera.
没有摄像头
No trace evidence left behind. And his escape is assured.
不会留下任何作案痕迹
Now, I'm not saying that he couldn't have killed
能轻松地逃走
those people at the river, but he wouldn't have.
他不可能在河边杀死那些人
Not that way.
他不会用这种方式干
- So you're saying he's crazy. - No.
-那么 你是说他疯了 -不是
Well, what exactly are you saying?
那你是什么意思
Any single piece of evidence I'd buy. But all of it?
我相信任何证据
Fibres, fingerprints, stray brass, I mean...
纤维 指纹 飞走的弹壳 连起来呢
And who the hell pays for parking?
究竟是谁付的停车费
Sane or crazy, that just doesn't make sense.
神志是否正常
Okay. So Barr, he wanted to get caught and he wanted you to catch him.
这都解释不通 巴尔想让人抓住她
That would not explain how Barr,
-他想让你去抓他 -这也解释不了
an average shooter firing in poor conditions, never missed.
巴尔怎么会在那种情况下开枪
He did miss.
而且还没有失手
He did.
他失手了
A pristine bullet,
崭新的子弹
conveniently trapped by a liquid backstop.
留在被击中的液体中
The same bullet that tied Barr's gun to the killings.
同样的子弹从巴尔的枪射击遇害者
And arguably the prosecution's single most important piece of evidence.
作为起诉书中重要证据是有争议的
If Barr wanted to get caught, he didn't miss.
如果巴尔想被抓住 他为何没有失手
Either way, it doesn't make sense.
这解释不通
If he wanted to get away with it, he likely would have
如果他想逃 早就逃了
and if he wanted to get caught,
如果他想被人抓住
Barr was incapable of such perfection.
巴尔不可能做到这么完美
Or maybe he just got lucky, six shots out of six.
-或者说他运气很好 6枪6中
That's what I was willing to accept,
直到这些家伙抓住我之前
then those guys took a run at me.
我愿意接受这个观点
Whoever sent them made a mistake.
他们用错了人
It was just a bar fight.
那只是酒吧斗殴而已
Maybe.
也许
Or maybe someone got nervous, tried to run me off.
或者是有人害怕了 想把我吓走
Or put me in a coma, right next to their patsy.
或者把我打昏
Patsy?
放在容易受骗的人身边
It was such a great crime scene.
这么完美的犯罪现场
No one stopped to think it might be too great.
简直太完美了
Not Emerson.
爱默生没想
Not your father.
你父亲也没想
Not even Barr's own defence attorney.
甚至你也没想
But Barr knew I would,
都认为巴尔有罪
no matter how much I wanted it to be true.
巴尔知道我会怀疑
That's why he asked for me.
那就是他为什么要见我
Wait.
等等
Are you suggesting...
你是说
James Barr is innocent.
詹姆斯-巴尔 是无辜的
You can see what this is, can't you?
你知道这是什么想法吗
You've got a case in your hands
你接这个案子
that may be the last case you'll ever have
也许是你最后一个
and you'll do anything not to hit the bottom of it.
你却想方设法不结案
Helen.
海伦
You know, you never should have retired.
海伦 你就不该退役
Just, look. Listen.
听着
For all I know, you were standing at an intersection
据我所知 三天前
with a cardboard sign three days ago.
你还举牌子站在十字路口
And I hired you. Jesus, my father was right.
而我竟然雇用了你 我的父亲是正确的
- Helen. Helen. - It makes total sense now.
- 海伦 海伦 - 现在全明白了
It's the way you live, the way you move around.
海伦 你那种生活方式 到处游荡
You're just not cut out for the real world, are you?
你不适应现实生活 是吗
Are you afraid you'll end up like Barr?
你害怕会有巴尔那样的下场
- Helen. - Is that what this is?
-海伦 -这是什么
Look out the window.
看看窗外
No, I have work to do.
不我要工作要做你快走吧
- And you need to leave. - Just humour me. Okay.
来吧
Let go of me.
放开我
- Would you tell me what you see? - I see the same
告诉我你见到了什么
things I see every day.
我每天看过的东西
Well, imagine you've never seen it.
好吧 设想一下你从没见过这些
Imagine you've spent your whole life in other parts of the world
想像你是在另一个地方度过人生
being told every day you're defending freedom.
你为自由而战
And finally you decide you've had enough.
你终于无法忍受了
Time to see what you've given up your whole life for.
看看你为之奋斗的是什么
Maybe get some of that freedom for yourself.
为自己争取一些自由
Look at the people.
看看这些人
Now tell me which ones are free.
现在告诉我哪个是自由的
Free from debt.
没债的
Anxiety.
焦虑
Stress.
压力
Fear.
恐惧
Failure. Indignity. Betrayal.
失败 侮辱 背叛
How many wish they were born knowing what they know now?
人们都希望生来就知道现在的事
Ask yourself how many would do things
问问自己 有多少人愿意
the same way all over again?
反覆做同一件事
And how many would live their lives like me?
有多少人愿意像我这样生活
Now look at the silver Audi across the street,
看看对面街上的那辆奥迪车
the one that's been following me all day.
整天都在跟踪我
What does that prove?
那能证明什么
Here's the tag number. How long would it take you to run it?
这是车牌号 多久能查出车主
At this time of night? I don't know. An hour?
晚上 我不确定 一小时
Do it.
查吧
Do it, and then I'll leave.
查到后 我就离开
When?
什么时候
No, this is my problem now. I'll handle it.
不 这现在是我的问题 我来解决
Yeah?
是的
You're blown.
你暴露了
The lawyer's running the license plates.
律师正在查车牌
Yeah. So do it?
是的
Done.
完成了
Go to this address.
去这个住址
HELEN: All right, let’s just say that Barr didn't do it.
好吧 假如巴尔没干这事
Or did it 'cause someone put him up to it.
或是有人指使他干的
Either way, what have you got?
你有什么证据
Conspiracy.
是阴谋
Yeah, conspiracy to kill five random people?
预谋杀死五个平民百姓 没有动机
There's no motive.
很荒唐 是吗
- It's ridiculous, right? - It's grassy knoll ludicrous.
荒唐的有点离谱
No point looking any further.
进一步调查没有意义了
Exactly.
没错
What's this?
这是什么
The motive. Just hold onto it.
杀人动机
What are we playing, Clue?
我们在玩什么 猜迷游戏
Give it to me.
给我
Thank you.
谢谢
You sure that car was following you all day?
你确信那辆汽车跟了你一天吗
As soon as you picked me up. Why?
你接上 我就开始
It's registered to a company called Lebendauer Enterprises.
这辆车属于乐班德尔公司
A conspiracy to kill five random people?
预谋杀死五个平民
That's ridiculous.
荒唐
Four.
四个
Four random people.
四个平民
To hide one specific target.
为了掩盖一个特定的目标
REACHER: Someone needed Oline Archer's construction business.
有人想要奥赖恩-阿彻的建筑生意
And Oline wouldn't let it go.
而奥赖恩不愿意交出项目
It's a convincing theory.
这是一个合理的假设
But it's just a theory.
但是只是一个假设
The first round is the least accurate. The snipers call it a cold shot.
第一枪射击是最不准确的
Meanwhile, your eyewitness described a pause
狙击手称之为冷射 你的目击证人描述说
between the first and second rounds.
第一枪和第二枪之间有停顿
The one shot where the killer took his time.
第二枪射手很深稳
HELEN: And Oline Archer was the second victim.
奥赖恩-阿彻是第二个遇害者
The one shot that mattered.
这一枪 至关重要
But it's just a theory.
这还只是猜测
This frame was custom made for Barr.
这是根据巴尔习惯而设的圈套
Whoever chose him knew about Baghdad
选中他的人了解巴格达的事
and the only one who could have told him about Baghdad
而能讲出这件事的人
was Barr himself.
只有巴尔他自己
He has at least one friend. A very close one.
他至少会有一朋友 非常亲密的朋友
Now, you find that friend, you'll find the real shooter.
找到他 才能找真正的凶手
Find the real shooter? Reacher,
找到真正的凶手 雷彻
my job is to present the jury with reasonable doubt. Period.
我的工作是向陪审团提出合理质疑
What about catching the guys who really did this?
-要抓那些坏人 把他们绳之以法 -让他们接受法律制裁
- No, I can't take this to court. - Exposing the truth.
- 不 我不能拿这到法院 - 揭开事实真相
Even if I believed Barr is innocent, it's not my job.
即使我相信巴尔是无辜的
I am just a lawyer. I'm not a cop.
那不是我的工作 我只是一个律师而不是警察
And frankly, neither are you.
而且坦白说 你也不是
I can't do this any more.
我不能再这样做
Thanks for the coffee, counsellor.
谢谢你的咖啡 大律师
Sandy?
桑迪
Wait, it is Sandy, isn't it?
等等 是桑迪 不是吗
Do I know you?
我认识你吗
Charlie. Jeb's friend?
查理 杰布的朋友?
Oh, come on, don't break my heart.
太让我伤心了
I'm sorry, I don't remember.
对不起 我不记得
Well, we were both pretty wasted.
我们当时都喝高了
Oh.
哦 对
- What, you live here? - Just up there.
- 什么 你住在这儿 - 就在这楼上 真巧
I just moved in around the back! How crazy is that?
我刚刚搬到那后面住
It's wild.
难以置信 有趣
Yeah.
是啊
Wow! You look great.
哇 你真漂亮
Thanks.
谢谢
Well, look, you know, I don't want to keep you, so...
听着 我不想耽误你的时间
Maybe we can grab a drink sometime.
也许我们可以找个时间喝一杯
Yeah, maybe.
是的  也许
Hey, how about tonight?
今晚怎么样
I'm meeting some people.
我约了人
Okay. Well, some other time, then.
好吧
Some other time.
那就改天吧
Do it here.
在这里动手
What?
什么
HELEN: Reacher!
雷彻
There's a gun range in Ohio, targets out to 700 yards.
俄亥俄州有个射击场 目标距离700码
The only range that matches your requirements.
唯一符合你要求的场地
You should sleep.
你应该睡一会
You have a long drive tomorrow,
明天要开长途
and I need to go to city hall and pull up Oline's legal history.
我要查一下奥赖恩
I wouldn't do that. Not till I get back.
先别那样做
If I'm right, someone killed four random people
等我回来再说 如果我是对的 有人杀了四个平民
so no one would look directly at Oline.
目的不是让调查员去查奥赖恩
And if I'm right, just saying her name could get you killed.
如果我分析得对 只要提他的名字 你就会送命
- You saying I should be scared? - Well, are you smart?
- 你认为我会害怕吗 - 你很聪明 那不是明摆着的吗
Obviously.
显然
Then don't be scared.
那就不用害怕
What exactly am I looking for?
到底要我找什么
Someone who could kill that girl with one punch.
杀死这个女孩的人
Oh, you want the guy in 1109.
你要的人在1109室
Ernie Johnson.
厄尼-约翰逊
You'll see.
你要看看吗
Out of the car!
快下车
That's our suspect! Move, move!
他是我们要抓的嫌疑犯 快跑
Suspect is headed north on State Route 65.
疑犯在65号公路向北行驶
I need backup and air support.
我需要增援和空中支援
Hold up!
等一下
All clear!
没有人
Oh, God, I just don't believe it. I don't believe it!
哦 天呐 我就是不敢相信 不敢相信
I issued the warrant an hour ago.
我刚签发了逮捕令
According to the victim's boss,
有人看到雷彻
Reacher was seen at her place of work this morning.
今天去了她的商店
Where he threatened her boss.
他还威胁她老板
The car he was driving tonight belonged to a friend of Jeb Oliver's.
他开的是杰布-奥利沃朋友的车
The man he assaulted.
他打了那个人
No, those guys assaulted Reacher.
不 是他们打了雷彻
Reacher put three more men in the hospital
在杰布家
this afternoon at Jeb Oliver's place.
雷彻把三个人打伤住院
After arriving in Jeb Oliver's car.
是开杰布的车去的那里
And Jeb hasn't been seen since he left the hospital.
杰布出院后 再也没人看见他
Helen, if you know where Reacher is, you need to tell us.
如果你知道雷彻在哪  告诉我们
I don't know where he is. I have not seen him
我不知道 几个小时前 我离开办公室后
since he left my office a few hours ago.
就再也没见到他
- I think she's telling the truth. - Oh, you think, Dad? Fuck you!
- 我认为她说是的实话 - 你认为 爸 该死
Hey, I told you not to go near him.
我告诉过你不要接近他
You come into my home and you treat me like I'm an accessory!
你进入我的家就像审犯人一样审我
- Look, let me handle it. - I'm not done.
- 好了 我来处理 - 我没说完
You're both done. Just get out.
你俩说完了 出去
This is Helen.
这是海伦
REACHER: I'm guessing the police are there?
我猜警察在那里
Yep.
是的
By your response I'm guessing I have about 30 seconds
我猜不出30秒
before you hand them the phone.
他们就会要你手里的电话
If that.
会的
If you believe someone could frame Barr,
如果他们能陷害巴尔
you have to believe they could do the same to me.
也能陷害我
I suppose that's possible.
我想有这个可能
She was a sweet kid, Helen.
她是一个可爱的孩子 海伦
And they killed her because of me.
他们是因为我 才杀死了她
They want me to run.
他们逼我不插手此事
But I won't.
我决不
- I'm going to finish this. - No, that's not a good idea.
-我一定要查清 -这不是个好主意
Listen.
听好
Two things. One, I, uh...
第二
I stole your car.
我偷了你的汽车
If you want to end this,
如果你要结束合作
just hang up the phone and report it missing.
挂上电话报案 车丢了
And I'll understand.
我能理解
And anything else?
还有事吗
I thought I'd be pushing it if I mentioned this earlier.
早点告诉你怕你接受不了
Now I guess all bets are off.
我担心发生意外
You need to watch what you say to Emerson and your father.
对爱默生和你父亲谈话要小心
I think one of them is in on it.
我认为他们的其中之一参与了此案
All right. Thanks for calling. I have to go.
好  谢谢通知 我挂了
Wait. I've been followed from day one.
等等 从第一天开始 我就被跟踪了
Only three people knew I was here.
只有三个人知道我在这里
Emerson, your father and you.
爱默生，你的父亲和你
You need to ask yourself,
你自己想下
who has the most to lose if we clear Barr?
帮巴尔洗清罪名 谁损失最大
Who tried to warn you off me?
谁警告你要离开我
Of course, I could be wrong. If you think I am,
当然 我可能是错误的 如果你认为我是
just hand over the phone.
就挂上电话
There's no sense getting any deeper.
进一步调查就没有意义了
Who's that you're talking to?
你在和谁说话
The office.
办公室的人
Are we done?
我们谈完了吗
Helen, listen.
海伦 听着
- We need to... - Good night.
-我们需要 -晚安
You got some fine shooters here.
你这里有优秀的射手吗
Fine as frog's hair.
想找优秀的
Rarer, too.
很难
'Cause most of them fellas out there can't shoot worth a damn.
大多数来这儿的人 根本就不会射击
You ask them to put three rounds in the black, well,
让他们把3发子弹打中靶子
they'll suck it.
根本打不中
- I'm looking for the owner. - That'd be me. Martin Cash.
- 我要找店主 - 我就是 马丁-凯时
Aaron Ward.
艾伦-沃德
What can I do you for, Mr Ward? Ward?
我能为你做什么 先生
Yeah. I'm looking for a friend of mine. We served in Iraq.
我正在找一位我的朋友 一起在伊拉克服过役
The guy just dropped off the grid, you know?
他消失了 知道吗
- It happens. Yep. - Yeah. Yeah.
常有这种事
Anyway, he was a shooter.
他曾是名狙击手
Last I heard, he lived around here somewhere and I...
最后一次听到他的消息时 他还活着
When did he get out of the Army?
他什么时候退役的
Well, I didn't say the Army.
我没说他是军人
Well, you said you served with him. You're no jarhead.
你说过的 你是不是锅盖头
Man on a flying horse could see that.
明眼人一眼就能看出来
Well, my father was in the Corps, if that helps.
好吧 我的父亲是海军陆战队的
Well, (CHUCKLES) that makes you half human.
这只能说明你是半个强人
Your friend got a name?
你朋友的名字
Yeah. James Barr.
詹姆斯-巴尔
Never heard of him.
没听过
I think you have.
我认为你有
I think you've been dreading the moment
我认为你些恐惧
some cop comes in here asking after him.
警察来过
Because it's for sure some soccer mom around here
这让你很恐慌
is more worried about your range than she is about the pool in her backyard
这附近足球妈妈更担心你的射击场
or the drain cleaner under her sink.
而不是自家后院的游泳池
Wouldn't matter to her if Barr did his killing 100 miles away,
巴尔在100英里以外杀人也没什么
only that he came hereto rehearse.
可他是在你这儿训练的
She'd have a case to shut you down
足球妈妈一纸诉状就能让你停业
and nothing better to do.
你会无计可施
What do you want?
你想怎样
I want to know who Barr's friends were.
我想要知道巴尔的朋友是谁
Those boys out there,
这帮家伙
they're mighty touchy when it comes to their constitutional rights.
当你触动他们的权利里 他们很敏感
Suppose I tell them a cop is in here asking after my members?
告诉他们 警察问过我的会员会怎样
- I'm not a cop. - What are you?
- 我不是警官 - 你是作什么的?
I work for Barr's attorney.
我是巴尔的律师
We have reason to believe he's innocent.
我们有理由相信他是无辜的
The hell you say.
胡说 就算他是有罪
Be that as it may, I'm the only one who's bothered to track him this far.
我是唯一跑来调查他的人
You help me out, I'll be in your debt.
你帮我一次 我帮你解决债务问题
And if I don't?
而且如果不帮呢
Maybe you can coach soccer.
也许你能教足球
You put three in the centre and maybe we'll talk.
你把3发子弹打中靶心时我们再谈
Can I have a few to warm up?
能给几发热身吗
Six inches right.
偏右6英
That's your mulligan, Mr Ward. Play ball!
这是你的第二枪 沃德先生
Let's go.
准备 开始
You're a little rusty, Mr Reacher.
你的手有点生了 雷彻先生
I saw a man by that name shoot for the Wimbledon Cup,
十年前 有人用这个名子参加射击大赛
what, ten years ago.
什么 十年前
And I'm pretty sure you never played second base for the Yankees
我肯定你没打过扬基队的二垒手
in 1925.
在 1925 年
Now,
现在
I'll answer one question.
我将回答你的问题
Who's your best shooter?
谁是最好的射手
James Barr.
詹姆斯-巴尔
I pulled all these down as soon as I heard about the shooting.
听到他打死人 就把这些摘下来了
That's the best shot
那是人生平见过的
I ever seen this side of civilian life.
最棒的枪法
Suppose I told you Barr wasn't this good on his best day in the Army.
我告诉你 巴尔在部队也没打过这么好
I handed out those targets myself. That's my scrawl on every one.
这是我亲手贴上的靶子 上面有我的笔迹
Do you hang them downrange, too?
你也把靶子放在最远处吗
What, are you serious?
你是什么意思
I'm saying it's possible that Barr had a friend.
我是说巴尔可能有个朋友
One who switched the targets on the range.
他换掉了射击场里的靶子
Maybe Barr let him.
也许是巴尔让他换的
Made him feel like King Shit having his name up on your wall.
当他的大名挂在墙上 感觉自己是冠军
I never saw one real shooter who would do that for his own mother.
我从没见过一个真正的射手 会为了自己的妈妈这么做
Unless he was framing his mother for multiple murder
除非他想陷害她妈妈 杀了好几个人
and using your range to do it.
而且是在你这个射击场干的
Barr didn't come alone, did he?
巴尔不是一个人来的 对吗
You know, one of these nuts is likely to kill you, they find that camera, there.
如果他们发现录像 就会有人来杀你
Hell, the camera's there
录像就在这
'cause one of these nuts is likely to kill me.
没有疯子会杀我
There's Barr.
那是巴尔
I always liked him. Always liked him.
我一直很喜欢他
There.
在那里
Him.
他
That son of a bitch.
混蛋
Helen Rodin speaking.
海伦-罗丁
REACHER: Got a candidate for our shooter.
找到凶手备选人照片
Picture, possible prints
可能是他的指纹
and one pissed-off eyewitness.
还有个证人
I can't talk right now.
我现在不能说话
Just give me three hours to get back.
我3小时后回去
And don't talk to anyone until I get there.
这之前不要和任何人谈话
I'll look into that, thanks.
我会处理这事 谢谢
This is just what I could pull this morning.
这些是我今天早上拿到的资料
Tax records, city and state permit applications, contract bids.
纳税记录 市里和州里的项目批准书
Shell corporation in Georgia.
是格鲁吉亚一家空壳公司
That's the one next to Russia, not Florida.
挨着俄罗斯的国家 不在佛罗里达
They work one city at a time, acquiring a local construction concern
他们开发一个城市
just ahead of major civic redevelopment.
要求当地建筑公司在开工前
They build bridges no one needs. Highways no one uses.
先建造没人需要的桥梁 没人用的高速公路
They're like a cancer. A cell that won't stop growing.
他们像癌细胞一样不停地生长
They moved 12 times in 15 years. Atlanta, Albuquerque,
在15年里搬了12次家
Austin, Oklahoma City, Sacramento.
亚特兰大 阿尔布开克 奥斯汀 俄克拉荷马
Always amidst allegations of corruption
被指记账的名单中总是有它
including millions of dollars in missing public funds.
包括几千万公共资金不翼而飞
And yet never an investigation. Never even an inquiry.
可却从来未被调查过 甚至从没被质询过
It's as if Lebendauer Enterprises were above reproach.
这个公司口碑极佳
(SIGHS) Well, maybe that's because
也许那些是竞争对手的指责
the allegations come from the competition.
出高价
Outbid. Bitter.
充满敌意
Like Oline Archer.
比如奥赖恩-阿彻
Or maybe Lebendauer has the cooperation of key officials.
也许乐班德尔公司在跟重要部门合作
And maybe when that cooperation isn't enough,
合作不畅时 他们就杀掉那些收买不了的
they kill people who won't be bought off. Like Oline Archer.
比如奥赖恩
Helen, how much of this do you honestly believe?
这样的传言你相信多少
It doesn't matter how much I believe.
我相信多少没关系
It doesn't even matter how much I can prove.
甚至连我能证实多少都无关紧要
It only matters how much is true.
重要的是其中有多少是真的
Do you know how delusional you sound?
你知道吗 你这是幻听幻觉
What happened to you?
你怎么了
Are you really so set on putting this man to death that you'd ignore...
你真想他死吗
I pulled all of this paper under my own name.
所有的文件都是我自己获得的
If Jack Reacher's right,
如果杰克雷-彻说得对
my life, your daughter's life,
我的命 你女儿的生命
is in danger now.
现在有危险了
Whatever happens to me next is on your head,
我接下来出什么事都是你造成的
whether you're involved or not.
无论是不是与你有关
You are the District Attorney and I've given you compelling evidence
你是地方检察官 我已经给了你确凿的证据
to investigate Lebendauer Enterprises.
调查尔班德尔企业
Your next move will tell me which side you're on.
你的下个动作 将告诉我你的立场
Oh.
哦
I see. It's a test.
我知道了 这是一个测试
Well, this may be hard for you to believe, but I do love you.
好吧 我很难相信你 但是我爱你
And obviously I'm not going to turn a blind eye,
我不会视而不见的
no matter how absurd I find all of this.
无论我发现这些事有多么荒诞
So, if you really believe that you're in danger,
如果你真的相信你有危险
if you believe that,
如果你相信
then the next order of business,
那么接下来的任务
is to put you in protective custody right now.
就是马上对你进行保护监禁
And how safe will I be if you're part of it?
如果你也是同谋呢
Jesus, Helen.
天呐 海伦
Oh. Hey.
哦 嗨
Business meeting or personal?
公事还是私事
Hard to tell them apart.
很难分辨
I'll bet.
我打赌
Helen?
-海伦 -不是
Sorry, wrong number.
对不起 打错了
Is this Reacher?
你是雷彻吗
Who is this?
你是谁
It's you. The guy from the car.
是你 车里的人
It's your boyfriend.
是你的男朋友
Reacher, is it you?
雷彻 是你吗
Helen, are you hurt?
海伦 你受伤了吗
Well, she's gonna be if you're not here in one hour.
如果你一小时后不来 就废了她
Do I have to tell you how this works?
你追得我到处跑
You'll bounce me around to make sure I'm not followed,
怕我被虽人跟踪
then walk me into an ambush and kill me.
让我走进埋伏 杀掉我
Aw, you ruined my surprise.
你毁了我的惊喜
Well, I can do one better.
好 我会给你个更好的
I went down to the gun range at Hinge Creek.
我去过关键小溪射击场 拿到了照片和指纹
I got the picture, prints, and I'm going to the Feds.
我要去联帮调查局
The lawyer's all yours.
如果你敢动那个律师
Get the Zec.
叫翟科来
On second thought, I'd like to kill you.
我想杀了你
Let's say winner take all.
胜者为王
Listen to me, you prick.
听着 你这个混蛋
I will kill this bitch if you're not here in one...
你要是不过来 我就杀了这个婊子
Shit!
该死
You think I'm a hero?
你认为我是个英雄的
I am not a hero. I'm a drifter with nothing to lose.
我不是英雄 我只是个游侠
You killed that girl to put me in a frame.
你杀了那个女孩来陷害我
I mean to beat you to death and drink your blood from a boot.
我要扒了你的皮 喝干你的血
Now, this is how it's going to work. You're gonna give me the address
听着 这么办吧 你给我地址
and I'll be along when I am damn good and ready.
等我准备好了 就去找你算账
If she doesn't answer the phone when I call this number,
如果我打电话她不接
if I even think you've hurt her,
我会认为你杀了她
I disappear.
我就消失
And if you're smart, that scares you, because I'm in your blind spot
如果你聪明点 我不是威胁你 你在明我在暗
and I have nothing better to do.
而且我又没有别的事要做
You got a pen?
你有笔吗
Don't need one.
不需要
If I had a dollar for every time the Army called the Corps for help.
如果每次军方来找陆战队员帮忙 我都收一美元好了
- You have something for me? - Yeah.
- 你有东西给我 - 是的
Here.
在这
You're kidding, right?
你在开玩笑, 对不对
Just because I saw you shoot ten years ago
虽然我十年前看过你射击
doesn't mean I'll let you kill some asshole with my gun.
可并不意味着我会让你用我的枪
I told you how serious this was.
我告诉过你情况非常危急
And I showed up, didn't I?
我也被卷进去了 对吗
So let's get to it.
咱们大干一场吧
Now, your shooter will be
杀你的凶手会到这来
right up there behind those lights. Okay?
在那些灯光后面
He can cover both roads coming and going.
他能朝这条路射击
And kill you just as soon as you stand up.
你一站起来就能击毙你
Well, can you take him out?
好吧 你能干掉了吗
What, to dinner you mean?
什么 干掉他
Look, I don't know the type of people you normally associate with, Reacher.
听着 雷彻 我不知道你都和什么人交往
But I'm not in the habit of driving out to the boonies at the drop of a hat
我没那个习惯 毫无准备就走进荒野
and just picking off some total strangers, all right?
解决掉几个陌生人 好吗
Anyway, I can't see anything, not with them lights up.
那些灯太亮 我什么也看不清
So shoot them out.
那就打灭它
Yeah, sure. And then he knows right where I am.
可以 然后他就知道我在哪了
I might as well set myself on fire.
我这不是引火烧身吗
No, sir. I'll start shooting when he does.
不 先生 他开枪 我才开枪
And how do you propose we get him started?
你说我们引他先开枪怎么样
Well, you could always start running.
好吧  你可以开始跑了
What's wrong with your eye?
你的眼睛怎么了
I'm saving my night vision.
闭目养神
Hey, Gunny, you mind if I ask you kind of a personal question?
老牛仔 问你个私人问题
What, you don't think I can shoot any more?
你认为我不会再射击吗
It is a perishable skill.
好枪法很难保持一辈子
Yeah, well,
是啊
the sun will be up in an hour.
太阳一小时后就升起来了
Let's get going.
我们走
I heard them call you the Zec.
我听到他们叫你翟科
That means "prisoner."
那是囚犯的意思 是吗
Yes?
是的
Tell me, killing all those people,
告诉我 杀了这么多人
I have to believe the money you're making
我相信你赚的钱
can't possibly be enough to just...
不可能足够用来
Enough?
说够了吗
There is no such thing.
根本没有这回事
We take what can be taken.
我们只拿属于我们的东西
This is what we do.
我们就是这么做的
And you?
而你呢
This one I think I understand, but you?
他我能理解 可是你呢
Why'd you do it?
你是为什么
You make it sound like I had a choice.
我没得选择
Oh, didn't you?
你没有吗
You'll see.
你会懂的
You should know I've taken steps, that if anything happens...
你们应该知道 我们已经采取了措施
if anything happens to you, it will happen in front of your father
如果你发生意外 也会在你父亲面前
while he begs for your life.
他祈求留你一条小命
You should never have involved him.
现在你必须说服他忘掉这一切
Now you will have to convince him to forget, for your sake
为了你
and for his.
也为了他
You say nothing, but I see defiance in your eyes.
你不说话 我能看到你眼中充满了蔑视
That is a look I have seen many, many times.
这种眼神我见多了
When the soldier comes,
等那个大兵来了之后
when you watch how he dies, it will change you.
你亲眼看着他死去 那会改变你的想法
You will want to forget me then.
到时你就会想忘记我了
Reacher?
雷彻
REACHER: Are you okay?
你好吗
They're ready for you.
他们要杀你
They'd like to think so.
他们这么认为
Don't do this. Please don't do this. Not for me.
别来 不要为了我
Listen, Helen, they're not gonna
海伦, 他们不会伤害你的
hurt you until they have me. And that's never going to happen.
在没有抓到我之前
You hear me?
你听我说
You just hang in there.
你要坚持住
'Cause I'm coming to get you.
我会去救你
Now say you believe me.
快说你相信我
I believe you.
我相信你
This was a bad idea.
这是个馊主意
Any time now, Gunny.
老年仔 准备射击
Shit.
该死
Where the hell are you, Gunny?
你在哪里 老牛仔
Suck it!
臭手
You should go.
你该走了
REACHER: I know you're in there, Emerson.
我知道你是在那里 爱默生
It was staring me right in the face.
我有你的犯罪证据
The one piece that just didn't fit.
一个证据不能解释一切
The quarter.
硬币
Nobody would have thought to dump that meter.
没人想到计时表的硬币就是证据
Not even me.
连我都不会这么想
You were wrong about my father.
你错怪了我的父亲
I wouldn't make a big thing of it.
我不会扩大事态
Who is he?
他是谁
That's John Doe Number Two.
他是二号人物
The man on the grassy knoll. The thing under the bed.
暗杀行动的策划者
They call him the Zec.
他们叫他翟科
Zec? Prisoner.
翟科 就是囚犯
What's your real name?
你的真正名字是什么
I was born in October.
我是十月出生的
When I get to my birthday, I'm gonna pull the trigger.
当我数到我生日的那月 我就开枪
One. Two.
一  二
Chelovek. Zec Chelovek.
切诺维克
Chelovek?
切诺维克 翟科-切诺维克
Chelovek? Human.
切诺维克是人名
Prisoner Human Being.
你叫囚犯人
- That's your real name? - That is all I remember.
- 那是你的真名吗 - 我就记得这些
Call the police.
打电话给警察
Were you really going to shoot him?
你刚才真想杀了他吗
I knew I wouldn't have to.
不会的
One look at this guy and you know he'll do anything to survive.
看一眼就知道会是想活的人
One look at me and you know I'm not bluffing.
你看一眼就知道我不是吹牛的人
Yes, I have an emergency at...
我有件急事
Yes, I'll hold.
好 我等着
We're in no hurry.
我们不着急
With a name like yours, you're gonna feel right at home.
你住监狱 就像在家里一样舒服
Prison? In America?
监狱 在美国
A retirement home. If I go to prison at all.
能去美国监狱 就像住进养老院
You think you're gonna walk?
你认为能逃脱罪名吗
You are a homeless drifter wanted for murder.
你是个无家可归的人 被通缉的杀人犯
Meanwhile, I am an old man in the wrong place at the wrong time.
我是在错误时间来这里的老头
Thanks to you, who is left to say otherwise? Who?
多亏了你
HELEN: Yes, hello? Yes, there's... I have an emergency.
谁呢 对 我有一件急事
We'll see which one of us goes to prison.
我们走着瞧 看谁进监狱
There are maybe three, four people dead.
也许有三四个人死
- Okay. - My bet?
- 好 - 我的打赌
Neither one.
没人
What did you do?
你做了什么
What's it look like?
这现场看上去像什么
What about the truth?
那真相怎么办
What about getting the guys who really did this?
怎么才能抓到真到的凶手
What about bringing him to justice?
将他们绳之以法
I just did.
我刚刚做完了
HELEN: What about clearing Barr? What about clearing you?
怎样洗清巴尔的罪名
REACHER: I have faith you'll sort it out.
洗清你的罪名
And I hear you have an in with the local D.A.
你会解决的 我听说你当上了检察官
HELEN: But what happens to you in the meantime?
这期间你会干什么去
I keep moving. Same as always.
和以前一样 继续流浪
Wait, is that my car?
等等 那是我的汽车吗
This the lady?
这位女士
Helen Rodin, Martin Cash.
海伦-罗丁,马丁-凯时
A pleasure.
幸会
You look like hell there, Army.
你看起来糟透了 大兵
You asked if I was afraid I'd end up like Barr. I'm not.
你问我是不是害怕象巴尔那样的结果
I'm afraid I'll end up like this guy.
我不怕 我恐怕最终会像这家伙一样
There's a lot of dead bodies out here. So let's get to it.
这里有好几具尸体 咱们走吧
- We should probably go. - Wait. That's it?
- 我们该去哪儿呢 - 等等 这就完了
It's just over?
结束了吗
You'll be all right, counsellor.
你会没事的 大律师
No. What if I need you? How will I find you?
不 我需要你的时候怎么办
You don't need me.
你不需要我了
Not any more.
不需要了
Get her number. Let's go!
记下她的电话号友 我们走
I'm Helen Rodin, your attorney.
我是海伦-罗丁 你的律师
This conversation is protected by attorney-client privilege.
本次谈话受律师诉讼委托人权益保护
You understand what that means?
你明白这什么意思吗
Yeah.
是的
Now, the police didn't talk to you, did they?
警察没找你谈过话 对吗
They're not allowed to do that without me here.
没有我在场 他们不能和你谈话
How bad was it?
情况多严重
How many did I...
有多少人
You don't remember anything about the incident?
你不记得那件事了
No.
不记得
But I could hear the nurses talking to those cops out there.
我听到护士和警察在外面的谈话
(SOBBING) I don't even remember wanting to do it!
我不记得自己为什么要杀人
Look, I'm not gonna fight this.
这一点我不抗辩
If they say I done it, then I did.
如果他们说是我干的 那我就干了
I done things before.
以前我也干过这事
I did something bad.
我做了坏事
Real bad.
很坏
A long time ago.
很久以前
And I got away with it.
我逃脱了罪名
James,
詹姆斯
how well do you know this place?
这地方你熟吗
Pretty well.
很熟悉
And how do you think you would have done it?
要是你做 你会怎么做
I guess
我猜
I would have parked up on the highway.
我会把车停在调整公路上
The sun would be at my back that time of day.
让太阳照在我背上
I got a van.
我有面包车
Set up in back.
枪架在车后部
Wouldn't have to worry about my brass.
用不着担心弹壳会飞出去
Get away real clean, too.
不留痕迹你 说我这么做对吗
Sounds as if you know your stuff.
听上去你是行家
I forget your name.
我忘记你的名字
It's Helen.
海伦
Helen Rodin.
海伦-罗丁
You're going to be okay, James.
你会没事的 詹姆斯
I am gonna take care of you.
我会保护你
You can't protect me.
你不能保护我
No one can.
没有人能 有人要害我
From what?
什么
From who?
谁
There's this guy.
有个人
He's a kind of cop.
他好像是警官
At least he used to be.
至少他过去是
He doesn't care about the law.
他不在乎法律
He doesn't care about proof.
不在乎证据
He only cares about what's right.
只在乎什么是公正
BARR: He knows what I did.
他知道我做什么
He knows where I am.
他知道我在哪里
And this guy, he made me a promise.
他向我承诺过
MAN: - I said, shut your mouth! (SLAP)
如果我再遇到麻烦
he'd be there.
他会来救我